Register of the Ardashīr Zāhidī papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Ambassador to the United States File, 1970-1979
  - Embassy files, 1970-1978
    - State visit files, 1973-1975
      - 1975 (Box 60, Folder 6-11)
        Includes correspondence and documents related to the logistics, meetings (including journalists, educators, and business people), and social events of the Shah and Shahbanu's 1975 visit to the United States, booklet printed by the Embassy, and copies of the Shah's letter to President Ford.
      - Dinners, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 12)
        Consists of invitation drafts, guest lists, and correspondence.
      - Farah Pahlavi at Georgetown University, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 13-14)
        Includes drafts of Farah's speech and other materials related to the Queen's honorary degree from Georgetown University.
      - Invitation list, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 15-16)
      - Press, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 17-18, Box 61, Folder 1)
        Includes correspondence with and about journalists, guest and invitation lists, and a copy of the Department of State "Correspondents List."
      - Farah Pahlavi, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 2-5)
        Includes telegrams to the Queen; Zahedi's correspondence with the Aspen Institute of Humanistic Studies, the Mayo Clinic, poiticians, and hospitality and security staff; itinerary and logistical documents; and the text of a speech delivered to the Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies during Farah Pahlavi's visit to the United States.
    - US governors correspondence, 1973-1976
      - Andrus, Cecil D., 1976 (Box 61, Folder 6)
      - Askew, Reubin O'D., 1973-1975 (Box 61, Folder 7)
      - Blanton, Ray, 1975-1976 (Box 61, Folder 8)
      - Bond, Christopher S., 1976 (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Briscoe, Dolph, 1973-1976 (Box 61, Folder 10)
      - Brown, Jerry, 1976 February (Box 61, Folder 11)
      - Busbee, George, 1975-1976 (Box 61, Folder 12)
      - Carey, Hugh L., 1975-1976 (Box 61, Folder 13)
      - Carroll, Julian M., 1975-1976 (Box 61, Folder 14)
      - Pryor, David, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 15)
      - Ray, Robert D., 1976 (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - General correspondence, 1972-1977
      - Acheson, David C., 1974-1976 (Box 61, Folder 17)
        Includes correspondence with Patricia Acheson.
      - Aga Khan, Sadruddin, Prince, 1973-1976 (Box 61, Folder 18)
      - Agnew, Spiro T., 1975-1976 (Box 61, Folder 19)
      - Alsop, Susan Mary, 1974-1976 (Box 61, Folder 20)
      - Annenberg, Walter H., 1975-1976 (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Atherton, Alfred L., 1975-1976 (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - Bailey, Pearl, 1973-1976 (Box 62, Folder 3-12)
        Includes accompanying photographs of Bailey with Gerald and Betty Ford, copies of a speech and press release from her time as special ambassador to the United Nations, and documents related to Iran travel.
      - Bellinger, Christiane and Robert, 1973-1976 (Box 62, Folder 13)
      - Bellonby, Dorcas E., 1976 (Box 62, Folder 14)
      - Bjurstrom, Betty, 1976 October (Box 62, Folder 15)
      - Bossom, Clive, 1976 (Box 62, Folder 16)
      - Braden, Joan and Thomas, 1974-1976 (Box 63, Folder 1, Box 62, Folder 17)
      - Bradley, Tom, 1973-1976 (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Brown, George S., 1974-1976 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1976 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Buchanan, Wiley T., 1973-1975 (Box 63, Folder 5)
        Includes correspondence with Ruth Buchanan.
      - Buchen, Philip W. and Bunny, 1974-1976 (Box 63, Folder 6-10)
      - Bunker, Ellsworth, 1976 January (Box 63, Folder 11)
      - Burger, Warren E., 1974-1976 (Box 63, Folder 12)
      - Burns, Arthur F., 1974 September (Box 63, Folder 13)
        Letter is actually from Helen Burns.
      - Bush, George, 1974-1977 (Box 63, Folder 14)
        Includes letters from Barbara Bush.
      - Butt, Hugh R., 1975-1976 (Box 64, Folder 1)
        Includes copy of "A Memorandum of Understanding Between Mayo Clinic-Mayo Foundation and the Imperial Medical Center of Iran."
      - Butz, Earl L., 1973-1976 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Çağlayangil, İhsan Sabri, 1976 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Callaghan, James, 1976-1977 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Callaway, Howard H., 1973-1976 (Box 64, Folder 5-6)
      - Catto, Henry E. and Jessica, 1974-1976 (Box 64, Folder 7-9)
      - Chase, Daryl, 1975-1976 (Box 64, Folder 10)
      - Colby, William Egan, 1973-1975 (Box 64, Folder 11)
      - Connally, John Bowden, 1973 (Box 64, Folder 12)
      - Cook, Philip S., 1974-1976 (Box 64, Folder 13-14)
        Includes correspondence with Val Cook.
      - Coyne, Marshall B., 1974-1975 (Box 64, Folder 15)
      - Dahl, Arlene, 1973-1976 (Box 64, Folder 16)
        Includes correspondence with Rounsevelle W. Schaum.
      - Daly, Patrick J., 1975 (Box 64, Folder 17)
      - Daley, Richard J., 1975 July 14 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      - Dickerson, C. Wyatt and Nancy, 1973-1976 (Box 65, Folder 2-3)
      - Doudell, Elizabeth, 1975-1976 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Douglas, Kirk, 1976 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - Dudley, Drew, 1976 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Duke, Angier Biddle and Robin, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 7-8)
      - Ellsworth, Robert F., 1976 (Box 65, Folder 9)
        Includes copies of letters from General Hassan Toufanian to Joseph G. Gavin and Erich von Marbod.
      - Englund, George, 1976 (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Fish, Howard M., 1975-1976 (Box 65, Folder 11)
        Includes photograph of Zahedi with James R. Cowan and Carlyle E. Maw.
      - France, Bill, 1975-1976 (Box 65, Folder 12-13)
        Includes text from Zahedi's speech given at the Congressional Medal of Honor Society banquet in Daytona, Florida.
      - Gerling, Victoria, 1973-1976 (Box 65, Folder 14-15)
      - Gorog, William F., 1975-1976 (Box 65, Folder 16)
      - Gray, Robert K., 1973-1976 (Box 65, Folder 17)
      - Griffiths, Eldon, 1973-1976 (Box 65, Folder 18)
      - Haig, Alexander Meigs, 1973-1974 (Box 65, Folder 19)
      - Hartmann, Robert T., 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 20, Box 66, Folder 1)
        Includes correspondence with Roberta S. Hartmann.
      - Healey, Denis, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Helms, Richard, 1973-1976 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Henderson, Loy W., 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Herring, Joanne and Robert, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 5-7)
      - Hilson, Mildred, 1976 (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - Hope, Anthony and Judith, 1976 (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Hope, Bob, 1976 (Box 66, Folder 10)
      - Ikard, Frank Neville and Jayne, 1973-1976 (Box 66, Folder 11-13)
        Includes a photograph of Zahedi with Muḥsin Ṣādiq Isfandiyārī.
      - Ingersoll, Robert S., 1975 (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Jameson, Frank G. and Eva Gabor, 1974-1976 (Box 67, Folder 1-3, Box 66, Folder 15-16)
        Includes copy of letter of understanding between the Ministry of Agriculture and Natural Resources of Iran, the Agricultural Development Bank of Iran, and Lidco Global Inc..
      - Jamieson, J. K., 1973-1974 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - Jaworski, Leon, 1976 June (Box 67, Folder 5)
      - Johnson, Lady Bird, 1973-1976 (Box 67, Folder 6-8)
        Includes Iran travel itinerary.
      - Jones, David C., 1976 (Box 67, Folder 9)
      - Kauffman, John H. and Patricia, 1973-1976 (Box 67, Folder 10-11)
      - Kennedy, Ethel, 1975-1976 (Box 67, Folder 12)
      - Kissinger, Henry, 1973-1974 (Box 67, Folder 13-14)
        Includes copies of Kissinger's correspondence with the Shah and photographs from Kissinger's swearing-in ceremony.
      - Laird, Melvin R., 1973-1976 (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - LeBaron, Robert and Peggy, 1973-1976 (Box 68, Folder 1-3)
      - Lindsay, John V., 1973-1976 (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - Lord, Shirley, 1973-1976 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Luns, Joseph M. A. H., 1973 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - MacArthur, Douglas, 1975-1976 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Marshall, Sylvan M., 1973-1976 (Box 68, Folder 8-12)
        Includes correspondence with Mara Marshall, copy of document designating Sylvan Marshall as Legal Consultant to the Embassy, and a photograph of Zahedi.
      - Mason, James and Clarissa Kaye, 1973-1976 (Box 68, Folder 13)
      - McCarthy, Eugene J., 1976 November (Box 68, Folder 14)
      - McLucas, John L., 1973-1975 (Box 68, Folder 15)
      - Meyer, Armin H., 1976 (Box 68, Folder 16)
      - Middendorf, John William, 1974-1976 (Box 68, Folder 17)
      - Mondale, Walter F., 1975-1976 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Moorer, Joseph P., 1976 December 28 (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Moorer, Thomas H., 1974-1976 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Morton, Rogers C. B., 1976 (Box 69, Folder 4)
        Letters are from Anne Morton.
      - Mosbacher, Emil, 1973-1976 (Box 69, Folder 5-6)
      - Nielsen, Natalie, 1976 (Box 69, Folder 7)
      - O'Brian, Hugh, 1973-1975 (Box 69, Folder 8-9)
      - Olds, Glenn A., 1975-1976 (Box 69, Folder 10)
      - Orfila, Alejandro, 1976 (Box 69, Folder 11)
      - Parsky, Gerald L., 1976 (Box 69, Folder 12)
      - Peacock, Andrew, 1976 (Box 69, Folder 13)
      - Peck, Gregory, 1976 (Box 69, Folder 14)
      - Philip-Sörensen, Jörgen and Sven, 1973-1976 (Box 69, Folder 15)
      - Powell, Lewis F., 1973-1976 (Box 69, Folder 16)
      - Ramsbotham, Peter and Frances, 1976-1977 (Box 69, Folder 17)
      - Reagan, Ronald, 1973-1976 (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - Richardson, Elliot L., 1973-1976 (Box 69, Folder 19-20)
      - Robb, Lynda J., 1975-1976 (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Roberts, B. K., 1973-1976 (Box 70, Folder 2-4)
        Includes correspondence with Mary Roberts.
      - Rockefeller, David, 1975 (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman, 1976 (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1974-1976 (Box 70, Folder 7-8)
      - Rogers, William P., 1972-1976 (Box 70, Folder 9-13)
        Includes correspondence with Adele Rogers; copy of communique between Bank Melli Iran, the Industrial and Mining Development Bank of Iran, and Merill Lynch; and copy of memo from Lacks V. Sepahbodi.
      - Roosevelt family, 1973-1975 (Box 70, Folder 14, Box 71, Folder 1)
        Includes correspondence with Archibald, Felicia, Kermit, and Selwa Roosevelt.
      - Roosevelt, Archibald, 1975 August 8 (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - Roosevelt, Kermit, 1976 (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Rumsfeld, Donald, 1974-1976 (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Rush, Kenneth, 1973-1976 (Box 71, Folder 5-6)
        Includes letters from Jane Rush.
      - Saunders, Harold H., 1973-1974 (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - Scheibel, Kenneth, 1974-1976 (Box 71, Folder 8-9)
      - Schlesinger, James R., 1973-1976 (Box 71, Folder 10)
      - Schott, Robert R., 1975 (Box 71, Folder 11)
      - Scowcroft, Brent, 1973-1976 (Box 71, Folder 12-13)
      - Scranton, William Warren, 1974-1976 (Box 71, Folder 14)
      - Shawcross, Hartley, 1973-1976 (Box 72, Folder 1-2, Box 71, Folder 15-16)
        Includes correspondence with Jane Shawcross.
      - Shepard, Tazewell, 1973-1976 (Box 72, Folder 3-4)
      - Shore, Dinah, 1976 October (Box 72, Folder 5)
      - Shouse, Catherine Filene, 1976 September 23 (Box 72, Folder 6)
      - Shriver, Eunice Kennedy, 1975 March 8 (Box 72, Folder 7)
      - Simon, William E., 1973-1976 (Box 72, Folder 8)
      - Sisco, Joseph J., 1973-1976 (Box 72, Folder 9)
        Includes correspondence with Jean Sisco.
      - Smith, Cissy, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 10)
      - Smoak, Marion H., 1973-1976 (Box 72, Folder 11-12)
        Includes correspondence with Frances Smoak.
      - Soames, Christopher, 1973-1976 (Box 72, Folder 13)
      - Sober, Sidney, 1976 December 21 (Box 72, Folder 14)
        Letter is to Elizabeth Sober.
      - Stewart, Potter, 1974-1976 (Box 72, Folder 15)
      - Strauss, Robert S. and Helen, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 16)
      - Swearingen, Bonnie and John E., 1973-1976 (Box 72, Folder 17-18, Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Talbot, Phillips, 1973-1974 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Taylor, Elizabeth, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 3)
        Correspondence with and about Elizabeth, including with Sara Sothern.
      - Temple, Shirley, 1973-1976 (Box 73, Folder 4)
        Includes copies of song lyrics written about Zahedi.
      - Tree, Marietta, 1975 December 22 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - Twitchtell, Hamilton A., 1975-1976 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      - Waldheim, Kurt, 1974-1976 (Box 73, Folder 7)
      - Warne, William E., 1976 and undated (Box 73, Folder 8)
      - Washington, Walter E., 1973-1976 (Box 73, Folder 9)
      - Yost, Charles Woodruff, 1975 December (Box 73, Folder 10)
      - Zulueta, Philip Francis de, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 11)
      - Zumwalt, Elmo R., 1973-1974 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Press correspondence, 1973-1976
      Consists of correspondence with editors, journalists, publishers, and other media figures.
      - Agronsky, Martin, 1976 December (Box 73, Folder 13)
      - Allbritton, Joe L., 1974-1976 (Box 73, Folder 14)
        Includes letters from Barbara Allbritton.
      - Alsop, Joseph, 1973-1976 (Box 73, Folder 15-17)
        Includes correspondence with Susan Mary Alsop.
      - Bartlett, Charles Leffingwell, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 18)
        Includes letters from Martha Bartlett.
      - Beale, Betty, 1973-1976 (Box 73, Folder 19)
      - Borchgrave, Arnaud de, 1973-1976 (Box 74, Folder 1-2)
        Includes correspondence with Alexandra Villard de Borchgrave.
      - Braun, Jonathan, 1975-1976 (Box 74, Folder 3-4)
        Includes issue of Parade with Farah Pahlavi interview.
      - Brinkley, David and Susan, 1973-1976 (Box 74, Folder 5-7)
      - Brokaw, Tom, 1976 January (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Buchwald, Art, 1975-1976 (Box 74, Folder 9)
      - Chambers, Winnie, 1976 (Box 74, Folder 10)
      - Chancellor, John, 1975-1976 (Box 74, Folder 11)
      - Chandler, Otis, 1974-1976 (Box 74, Folder 12)
        Includes correspondence with Marilyn Chandler.
      - Childs, Marquis W., 1973 August (Box 74, Folder 13)
      - Clark, Deena, 1973-1976 (Box 74, Folder 14)
      - Cooley, John K., 1973 (Box 74, Folder 15)
      - Cronkite, Walter, 1975 October 10 (Box 74, Folder 16)
      - Daniel, Clifton, 1973-1976 (Box 74, Folder 17-18)
      - Dixon, Ymelda C., 1973-1976 (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Epstein, Eleni and Sidney, 1974-1976 (Box 75, Folder 2-3)
      - Evans, Rowland, 1974 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - Foltz, Charles S., 1973-1974 (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Forbes, Malcolm S., 1976 (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - Friendly, Alfred and Jean, 1973-1975 (Box 75, Folder 7)
      - Fritchey, Clayton, 1975-1976 (Box 75, Folder 8)
      - Geyelin, Philip L. and Sherry, 1973-1976 (Box 75, Folder 9)
      - Giles, Frank, 1973-1976 (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - Goodman, Julian, 1975-1976 (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - Graham, Katharine, 1973-1976 (Box 75, Folder 12-13)
      - Hartz, Jim, 1975 December (Box 75, Folder 14)
      - Hearst, William Randolph, 1975-1976 (Box 75, Folder 15)
        Includes correspondence with Joseph Kingsbury-Smith and others affiliated with Hearst Newspapers.
      - Heiskell, Andrew, 1974-1976 (Box 75, Folder 16)
      - Jennings, Peter, 1975 (Box 75, Folder 17)
      - Kingsbury-Smith, Joseph, 1975-1976 (Box 75, Folder 18)
      - Kraft, Joseph, 1973-1976 (Box 76, Folder 1)
      - Leonard, Bill and Kappy, 1976 (Box 76, Folder 2)
      - Levine, Irving R., 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - Linen, James A., 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 4)
      - McElwaine, Sandra, 1973-1976 (Box 238, Box 76, Folder 5-6)
        Town & Country article by McElwaine about Zahedi in Box 238.
      - Monroe, Bill, 1975 (Box 76, Folder 7)
      - Moyers, Bill D., 1975 (Box 76, Folder 8)
      - Murphy, Franklin D., 1973-1976 (Box 76, Folder 9)
      - Paley, William S., 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 10)
      - Povich, Maury, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 11)
      - Quinn, Sally, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 12)
      - Rose, Kenneth, 1971-1976 (Box 76, Folder 13)
      - Rowan, Carl T. and Vivien, 1974-1976 (Box 76, Folder 14)
      - Safire, William, 1974-1975 (Box 76, Folder 15)
      - Scali, John, 1975 October (Box 76, Folder 16)
      - Schlosser, Herbert S., 1975-1976 (Box 76, Folder 17)
      - Shalit, Gene, 1975-1976 (Box 76, Folder 18)
      - Smith, Howard K., 1975 April (Box 76, Folder 19)
      - Spivak, Lawrence E., 1973-1974 (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - Stackelberg, Garnett, 1973-1976 (Box 77, Folder 2-3)
      - Stone, Martin L., 1974-1976 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Stroud, Kandy, 1974-1976 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - Sulzberger, C. L., 1973-1976 (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Includes correspondence with Arthur Ochs Sulzberger.
      - Swinton, Stanley M., 1973-1976 (Box 77, Folder 7-8)
        Includes correspondence with Helen Swinton.
      - Thomas, Lowell, 1974-1976 (Box 77, Folder 9)
      - Valenti, Jack, 1973-1976 (Box 77, Folder 10)
      - Valeriani, Richard, 1974-1976 (Box 77, Folder 11)
      - Wallace, Mike, 1974-1975 (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - Wallach, John, 1973-1975 (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - Walters, Barbara, 1974-1976 (Box 77, Folder 14-15)
      - Weadon, Donald A., 1973-1976 (Box 78, Folder 1)
        Includes correspondence with Donald Weadon Senior and Junior.
    - Unfiled correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs of Zahedi with Elizabeth Burton.
    - 1976 Christmas files
      - Gift lists, 1976 (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Delivery receipts, 1976 (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Includes gift lists, guest lists, and receipts.
      - Gifts and cards received, 1976 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - 1977 White House correspondence
      - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1977 (Box 78, Folder 7-8)
      - Clough, Susan, 1977 November (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - Gorog, William F., 1977 (Box 78, Folder 10)
      - Hoyt, Mary Finch, 1977 (Box 78, Folder 11-12)
        Includes text of Rosalynn Carter's remarks from lunch honoring Farah Pahlavi.
      - Jordan, Hamilton, 1977 (Box 78, Folder 13)
      - Mondale, Walter F., 1977 (Box 78, Folder 14)
      - Poston, Gretchen, 1977 (Box 78, Folder 15)
      - Powell, Jody, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Schlesinger, James R., 1977 November 19 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - Scowcroft, Brent, 1977 January (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - Watson, Jack H., 1977 July (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - 1977 US State Department correspondence
      - Atherton, Alfred L., 1977 (Box 79, Folder 5)
        Includes message from Homa Zahedi.
      - Benson, Lucy W., 1977 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Bunker, Ellsworth, 1977 September (Box 79, Folder 7)
      - Daly, Patrick, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 8)
      - Dobelle, Evan and Kit, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 9)
      - Padgett, Dorothy, 1977 October (Box 79, Folder 10)
      - Sullivan, William H., 1977 (Box 79, Folder 11)
      - Vance, Cyrus R., 1977 (Box 79, Folder 12-13)
      - Young, Andrew, 1977 December 19-23 (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - 1977 US Department of Defense correspondence
      - Air Force, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 15)
      - Alexander, Clifford L., Jr., 1977 (Box 79, Folder 16)
      - Army, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 17)
      - Brown, Harold, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 18)
      - Navy, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 19-20)
        Includes correspondence with Paul C. Boyd, Robert L. J. Long, and Kinnaird R. McKee.
      - Stetson, John C., 1977 (Box 79, Folder 21)
    - 1977 US Government correspondence
      - Andrus, Cecil D., 1977 (Box 79, Folder 22)
      - Bell, Griffin B., 1977 (Box 79, Folder 23)
      - Bergland, Bob Selmer, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 24)
      - Blumenthal, W. Michael, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 25)
      - Burger, Warren E., 1977 (Box 79, Folder 26)
        Includes correspondence with other justices.
      - Coleman, William T., 1976-1977 (Box 79, Folder 27)
      - Harris, Patricia, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 28)
      - Kreps, Juanita M., 1977 October (Box 79, Folder 29)
      - Simon, William E., 1977 January 17 (Box 79, Folder 30)
      - Turner, Stansfield, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 31)
    - 1977 US Senate correspondence
      - Abourezk, James G., 1977 (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Baker, Howard H., Jr., 1977 (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Bartlett, Dewey F., 1977 (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Bayh, Birch, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 4-5)
      - Bentsen, Lloyd, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 6)
      - Brooke, Edward W., 1977 (Box 80, Folder 7)
        Includes correspondence about Reza Baraheni's relative, Narmin Baraheni.
      - Bumpers, Dale, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Byrd, Harry F., Jr., 1977 June 6-7 (Box 80, Folder 9)
      - Byrd, Robert C., 1977 (Box 80, Folder 10)
      - Cannon, Howard W., 1977 (Box 80, Folder 11)
      - Case, Clifford P., 1977 (Box 80, Folder 12)
      - Chiles, Lawton, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 13)
      - Church, Frank, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 14)
      - Clark, Dick, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 15)
      - Curtis, Carl T., 1977 (Box 80, Folder 16)
      - DeConcini, Dennis, 1977 October 21 (Box 80, Folder 17)
      - Dole, Robert J., 1977 (Box 80, Folder 18)
        Includes correspondence with Elizabeth Dole.
      - Eastland, James O., 1977 January 25-28 (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - Glenn, John, 1977 October-November (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Goldwater, Barry M., 1976-1977 (Box 80, Folder 21-22)
      - H, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 23)
      - Hart, Gary, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 24)
      - Hatfield, Mark O., 1977 (Box 80, Folder 25)
      - Heinz, John, 1977 July (Box 80, Folder 26)
      - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1977-1978 (Box 80, Folder 27)
        Includes correspondence with Muriel Buck Humphrey Brown.
      - Jackson, Henry M., 1975-1977 (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - Javits, Jacob K., 1977 (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - Kennedy, Edward M., 1977 (Box 81, Folder 3)
      - L, 1977 (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - M, 1977 (Box 81, Folder 5)
      - Mathias, Charles McC., 1977 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - McGovern, George S., 1976-1977 (Box 81, Folder 7-9)
        Includes memorandum by Zahedi related to anti-Shah protests and copies of supporting documents.
      - Nelson, Gaylord, 1977 November 25 (Box 81, Folder 10)
      - Nunn, Sam, 1977 (Box 81, Folder 11)
      - Pell, Claiborne, 1977 (Box 81, Folder 12)
      - Percy, Charles H., 1977-1978 (Box 81, Folder 13-14)
        Includes correspondence with Lorraine Percy.
      - Ribicoff, Abraham, 1977 (Box 81, Folder 15-17)
        Includes correspondence with Casey Ribicoff and "Senate Delegation Report on American Foreign Policy and Nonproliferation Interests in the Middle East: Report pursuant to Senate Resolution 167 of May 10, 1977," June 1977.
      - S, 1977-1978 (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - Schweiker, Richard S., 1977-1978 (Box 82, Folder 2)
      - Sparkman, John, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - T, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 4)
      - Thurmond, Strom, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 5)
      - Williams, Harrison A., Jr., 1977 July (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - 1977 US House of Representatives correspondence, 1977-1978
      - A, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 7)
      - B, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 8)
      - Bingham, Jonathan B., 1977 (Box 82, Folder 9)
      - Boggs, Lindy, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 10)
      - Brademas, John, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 11)
      - C, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 12)
      - Cohen, William S., 1977 (Box 82, Folder 13)
      - D (Box 82, Folder 14)
      - Findley, Paul, 1977-1978 (Box 82, Folder 15)
        Includes H. Con. Res. 284 on peace in the Middle East.
      - Fraser, Donald M., 1977 December (Box 82, Folder 16)
      - Holt, Marjorie, 1977 September-October (Box 82, Folder 17)
      - J, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 18)
      - Lehman, William, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 19)
      - Mahon, George Herman, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 20)
      - McDonald, Lawrence Patton, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 21)
      - Meeds, Lloyd, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 22)
      - Meyner, Helen S., 1977 (Box 82, Folder 23)
      - Montgomery, G. V., 1977-1978 (Box 82, Folder 24)
      - Murphy, John M., 1977 (Box 82, Folder 25)
      - Oakar, Mary Rose, 1977 April 2-4 (Box 82, Folder 26)
      - O'Neill, Tip, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 27)
      - Pepper, Claude, 1977 January (Box 82, Folder 28)
      - Pressler, Larry, 1977 (Box 82, Folder 29)